UWIMBABAZI KEZA

Ugandan | African Leadership University, Bumbogo, Kigali Rwanda | +250791504687 Email: u.keza@alustudent.com | Github: link | Portfolio: link

SUMMARY

Motivated problem solver keen on using technology to address inequality issues in Africa, with a focus on empowering women and people with disabilities (PwD). Skilled in UI/UX, Web Design, and Web and Mobile application development. Currently completing a Bachelor of Software Engineering Honours degree. Interested in research and pursuing further studies.

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

African Leadership University - Kigali, Rwanda

January 2022 – present

Bachelor of Software Engineering (Hons)

ALU Leadership Course: Entrepreneurial Leadership, Research, Computer Literacy, Communication for Impact,

BSE Foundations Coursework: Shell, GitHub & Git, Python, Networking, Web development (HTML, CSS, Javascript, React), Mobile Development (React Native, Flutter)

Machine Learning Specialization:

Mathematics for Machine Learning (Linear Algebra, Matplotlib, Calculus, Probability)

Introduction to Machine Learning (Classification, Tensorflow, Optimization, Regularization, Transfer Learning)

Machine Learning Pipeline (Neural Style Transfer, RNNs, NLP, Transformers)

Machine Learning Techniques (Unsupervised learning, Reinforcement Learning)

CERTIFICATES

ALX Data Analytics course ALX AI fundamentals March 2024 – August 2024 March 2024 – May 2024

PROFESSIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE

UI Design Intern

July 2023 – September 2023

Mobiklinic - Kampala, Uganda

- Reviewed former UI for Mobiklinic's health tech mobile application
- Designed new user-friendly UI/UX designs for future implementation.

Tech support Intern

April. 2021 – June 2021

Nakasero - Kampala, Uganda

- Provided daily support for end-user requests regarding software and hardware issues.
- Collected information for migration into a new hospital management software solution.
- Assisted in training employees on how to use the new hospital management software.
- Assisted in collecting information for equipment inventory.
- Installed and maintained new antivirus software.
- Drafted daily reports of tasks completed and problems solved.

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Volunteer, Rwanda National Union of the Deaf (RNUD)

October 2024 - Present

- Researching to improve communication and accessibility for the deaf community in Rwanda
- Building a Rwandan Sign Language Translator

Owner, "Bold"

July 2021– December 2021

Owned a small perfume business in my small hometown aimed at providing women with affordable quality perfume.

Assistant teacher, Bethany Children's Home Mthatha, South Africa

June 2017 - December 2019

- Developed and taught mathematics and English lessons to children between 7 and 13.
- Prepared and served lunch meals.
- Painted educational murals.

SKILLS

• Web Development

• Computer networking

• UI/UX Design

• React Native and Flutter Mobile Development